♪ (intro music) ♪
♪ (music) ♪
Flutter has a lot of widgets to help with explicit animations,
ones that you, the developer, code up.
But there are also widgets for implicit animations,
those that animate changes for you.
A good one to know is AnimatedContainer.
You can build it once with a particular attribute, like color.
And when you rebuild it with a different value,
say, in response to a setState call,
AnimatedContainer performs a linear interpolation
between the two values.
And it's more than just colors.
You can animate borders, border radii, background images,
shadows, gradients, shapes, padding, width, height,
alignment, transforms, and more.
The length of the animation is controlled by the duration parameter,
and you can also specify your own curve to customize the effect.
There are a bunch of other widgets to help with implicit animations, too.
So head to flutter.io for more info.
♪ (music) ♪